<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Notes | Aspiring Entrepreneur]]></title>
  <link href="http://yangsu.github.com/blog/categories/notes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yangsu.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-07T02:14:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://yangsu.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Yang Su]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chapter 2: The Psychology of Everyday Actions]]></title>
    <link href="http://yangsu.github.com/blog/2012/10/17/chapter-2-the-psychology-of-everyday-actions/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-17T17:20:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yangsu.github.com/blog/2012/10/17/chapter-2-the-psychology-of-everyday-actions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>If an error is possible, someone will make it. The designer must assume that all possible errors will occur and design so as to minimize the chance of error in the first place, or its effects once it gets made. Errors should be easy to detect, they should have minimal consequences, and, if possible, their effects should be reversible.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id='introduction'>Introduction</h2>

<p>This chapter of <a href='http://www.amazon.com/Design-Everyday-Things-Donald-Norman/dp/0465067107' title='The Design of Everyday Things'>The Design of Everyday Things</a> introduces and formalizes basic concepts and principles of design from observations of everyday objects. Why some objects, as simple as doors, please their users while others frustrate them.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>If a task appears simple or trivial, people blame themselves rather than faulty design.</p>

<p>People tend to find causes for events</p>

<ul>
<li>casual relationship between 2 things occurred in succession</li>

<li>perceived relationship between the result and the thing being blamed</li>
</ul>

<p>blame based on little or erroneous information ⇒ blame/credit can be asserted independent of reality</p>

<p>if everyone perceives the fault to be their own, nobody wants to admit to having trouble This creates a conspiracy of silence, maintaining the felling of guilt and helplessness among users</p>

<p>In general, people attribute</p>

<ul>
<li>their problems ⇒ the environment</li>

<li>problems of others ⇒ others&#8217; personalities</li>

<li>their successes ⇒ their personalities</li>

<li>successes of others ⇒ the environment</li>
</ul>

<h2 id='definitions'>Definitions</h2>

<ul>
<li>
<p><strong id='learned-helplessness'>Learned Helplessness</strong>: people experience failure at a task, often numerous times ⇒ conclude that they simply cannot do the task; they are helpless</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong id='taught-helplessness'>Taught Helplessness</strong>: failure at a task ⇒ generalization of failure at all tasks ⇒ not even trying at a task ⇒ failure at a task</p>
</li>
</ul>

<h2 id='how-people-explain-things'>How People Explain Things</h2>

<ul>
<li>with hindsight, it&#8217;s almost impossible to assess how the people could have made the mistake when the course of action is rather logical in that particular situation</li>

<li>explanations tend to be based on past experiences, which may not apply to the present</li>
</ul>

<h2 id='seven-stages-of-action'>Seven Stages of Action</h2>

<p><img alt='Seven Stages of Action' src='/images/2012-10-17-chapter-2/seven-stages-of-action.png' /></p>

<h3 id='gulfs'>Gulfs</h3>

<p>Each <em>gulf</em> reflects one aspect of the distance bteween the mental representations of the person and the physical components and states of the environment. These gulfs present major problems for users.</p>

<h4 id='the_gulf_of_execution'>The Gulf of Execution</h4>

<p>&#8220;measure of how well the system allows a user to perform the intended action&#8221;<br /><em>Ex.</em> how well does the system provide actions that correspond to the intentions of the person?</p>

<h4 id='the_gulf_of_evaluation'>The Gulf of Evaluation</h4>

<p>&#8220;measure of how much effort a user must exert to interpret the physical state of the system and how well the expectations are met&#8221;<br /><em>Ex.</em> Does the system provide a physical representation that can be directly perceived and that is directly interpretable in terms of the intentions and expectations of the person</p>

<h2 id='using_seven_stages_of_action_as_design_aids'>Using Seven Stages of Action as Design Aids</h2>

<h3 id='principles'>Principles</h3>

<ul>
<li><strong>Feedback</strong>: full, continuous Feedback about the result of actions</li>

<li><strong>Visibility</strong>: by looking, a user can tell the state of the device and laternatives for action</li>

<li><strong>Good Conseptual Model</strong>: consistency/coherenc in presentations of operations, results, system image</li>

<li><strong>Mapping</strong>: actions ⬄ results, controls ⬄ effects, system state ⬄ what&#8217;s visible</li>
</ul>

<h3 id='design_questions'>Design Questions</h3>

<p><img alt='Ask Design Questions using the Seven Stages' src='/images/2012-10-17-chapter-2/seven-stages-questions.png' /></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chapter 1: The Psychopathology of Everyday Things]]></title>
    <link href="http://yangsu.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/chapter-1-the-psychopathology-of-everyday-things/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T17:52:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yangsu.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/chapter-1-the-psychopathology-of-everyday-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The human mind is exquisitely tailored to make sense of the world. Give it the slightest clue and off it goes, providing explanation, rationalization, and understanding.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id='introduction'>Introduction</h2>

<p>This chapter of <a href='http://www.amazon.com/Design-Everyday-Things-Donald-Norman/dp/0465067107' title='The Design of Everyday Things'>The Design of Everyday Things</a> introduces and formalizes basic concepts and principles of design from observations of everyday objects. Why some objects, as simple as doors, please their users while others frustrate them.</p>
<!-- more -->
<h2 id='definitions'>Definitions</h2>

<ul>
<li>
<p><strong id='visibility'>Visibility</strong>: correct parts must be visible, they must convey the correct messages; indicates the mapping between <em>intended actions</em> and <em>actual operations</em></p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong id='affordance'>Affordance</strong>: the perceived and actual properties of the thing, primarily the fundamental properties that determine how it can be used. <em>Affords</em> = <em>&#8220;is for&#8221;</em></p>

<p><em>Examples</em>:</p>

<p><img alt='horizontal bar  pushing (www.vanseodesign.com/web-design/minimize-errors-part-i)' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/door-push-bar.jpeg' /></p>

<p><img alt='vertical bar  pulling (www.flickr.com/photos/redsquirrel/4870919966/sizes/m/in/photostream)' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/door-pull-handle.jpeg' /></p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong id='system-image'>System Image</strong>: the visible part of a device or system</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong id='mental-model'>Mental Models</strong>: the models people have for themselves, others, the environment, and things with which they interact. Formed through experience, training, instructions, or by interpreting perceived actions and the <a href='#system-image'>System Image</a></p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong>Mapping</strong> : the relationship between two things <em>Example</em>: controls ⇒ their resulting movements and the effects in the physical world</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong id='natural-mapping'>Natural Mapping</strong>: <a href='#mapping'>mapping</a> that takes advantage of physical/spatial analogies and cultural standards <em>Examples</em>:</p>

<p><img alt='Rising Level ⇒ More' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/rising-level.png' /> <img alt='Diminishing Level ⇒ Less' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/diminishing-level.png' /></p>

<p>- <strong>Additive Dimensions</strong>: add more to show incremental increases <em>Examples</em>: amount, loudness, weight, length, brightness, etc.</p>

<p>- <strong>Substitutive Dimensions</strong>: substitute one value for another to make a change <em>Examples</em>: pitch, taste, color, location</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong>Feedback</strong>: sending back information to users about what actions have been performed <em>Example</em>: <img alt='Phones provide lots of feedback' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/phone.png' /> - Tactile feedback of buttons - Tones mapped for each button - Clicks, tones, to inform state and progress of a call or operation - <em>Sidetones</em>, the voice signal feedback into the ear to help regulate loudness</p>
</li>
</ul>

<h2 id='principles-of-design'>Principles of Design</h2>

<ol>
<li>
<p>Provide a good conceptual model - The proper <a href='#system-image'>System Image</a> and immediate <a href='#feedback'>feedback</a> for each operation can help users form a clear, concise, and correct <a href='#mental-model'>mental model</a></p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Make Things Visible</p>

<ul>
<li>Use good <a href='#natural-mapping'>natural mappings</a> and proper <a href='#visibility'>visibility</a> to help the user understand of possible operations, their effects, and the system state</li>

<li>The number of controls should be ≧ the number of functions a device performs, so each can be specifically mapped to a particular function</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>

<h2 id='designers-responsibility'>Designer&#8217;s Responsibility</h2>

<p>The Designer must balance the conflicting needs of others that help realize a product design:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Manufacturer</em>: the product can be produced economically and efficiently</li>

<li><em>Store</em>: the product should be attractive to customers</li>

<li><em>Purchaser</em>: the price, appearance, prestige value of a product at the Store</li>

<li><em>User</em>: the functionality and usability of a product at home</li>

<li><em>Repairer</em>: the product&#8217;s maintainability; how easy it is to take apart, diagnose, and service</li>
</ul>

<h2 id='development-of-a-technology'>Development of a Technology</h2>

<p><img alt='Development of a Technology' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/development-of-a-technology.png' /></p>

<h2 id='the-paradox-of-technology'>The Paradox of Technology</h2>

<p>The same technology that simplifies life by providing more functions in each device also complicates life by making the device harder to learn and use</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
