<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: The Design of Everyday Things | Aspiring Entrepreneur]]></title>
  <link href="http://yangsu.github.com/blog/categories/the-design-of-everyday-things/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yangsu.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-07T02:14:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://yangsu.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Yang Su]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chapter 2: The Psychology of Everyday Actions]]></title>
    <link href="http://yangsu.github.com/blog/2012/10/17/chapter-2-the-psychology-of-everyday-actions/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-17T17:20:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yangsu.github.com/blog/2012/10/17/chapter-2-the-psychology-of-everyday-actions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>If an error is possible, someone will make it. The designer must assume that all possible errors will occur and design so as to minimize the chance of error in the first place, or its effects once it gets made. Errors should be easy to detect, they should have minimal consequences, and, if possible, their effects should be reversible.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id='introduction'>Introduction</h2>

<p>This chapter of <a href='http://www.amazon.com/Design-Everyday-Things-Donald-Norman/dp/0465067107' title='The Design of Everyday Things'>The Design of Everyday Things</a> introduces and formalizes basic concepts and principles of design from observations of everyday objects. Why some objects, as simple as doors, please their users while others frustrate them.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>If a task appears simple or trivial, people blame themselves rather than faulty design.</p>

<p>People tend to find causes for events</p>

<ul>
<li>casual relationship between 2 things occurred in succession</li>

<li>perceived relationship between the result and the thing being blamed</li>
</ul>

<p>blame based on little or erroneous information ⇒ blame/credit can be asserted independent of reality</p>

<p>if everyone perceives the fault to be their own, nobody wants to admit to having trouble This creates a conspiracy of silence, maintaining the felling of guilt and helplessness among users</p>

<p>In general, people attribute</p>

<ul>
<li>their problems ⇒ the environment</li>

<li>problems of others ⇒ others&#8217; personalities</li>

<li>their successes ⇒ their personalities</li>

<li>successes of others ⇒ the environment</li>
</ul>

<h2 id='definitions'>Definitions</h2>

<ul>
<li>
<p><strong id='learned-helplessness'>Learned Helplessness</strong>: people experience failure at a task, often numerous times ⇒ conclude that they simply cannot do the task; they are helpless</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong id='taught-helplessness'>Taught Helplessness</strong>: failure at a task ⇒ generalization of failure at all tasks ⇒ not even trying at a task ⇒ failure at a task</p>
</li>
</ul>

<h2 id='how-people-explain-things'>How People Explain Things</h2>

<ul>
<li>with hindsight, it&#8217;s almost impossible to assess how the people could have made the mistake when the course of action is rather logical in that particular situation</li>

<li>explanations tend to be based on past experiences, which may not apply to the present</li>
</ul>

<h2 id='seven-stages-of-action'>Seven Stages of Action</h2>

<p><img alt='Seven Stages of Action' src='/images/2012-10-17-chapter-2/seven-stages-of-action.png' /></p>

<h3 id='gulfs'>Gulfs</h3>

<p>Each <em>gulf</em> reflects one aspect of the distance bteween the mental representations of the person and the physical components and states of the environment. These gulfs present major problems for users.</p>

<h4 id='the_gulf_of_execution'>The Gulf of Execution</h4>

<p>&#8220;measure of how well the system allows a user to perform the intended action&#8221;<br /><em>Ex.</em> how well does the system provide actions that correspond to the intentions of the person?</p>

<h4 id='the_gulf_of_evaluation'>The Gulf of Evaluation</h4>

<p>&#8220;measure of how much effort a user must exert to interpret the physical state of the system and how well the expectations are met&#8221;<br /><em>Ex.</em> Does the system provide a physical representation that can be directly perceived and that is directly interpretable in terms of the intentions and expectations of the person</p>

<h2 id='using_seven_stages_of_action_as_design_aids'>Using Seven Stages of Action as Design Aids</h2>

<h3 id='principles'>Principles</h3>

<ul>
<li><strong>Feedback</strong>: full, continuous Feedback about the result of actions</li>

<li><strong>Visibility</strong>: by looking, a user can tell the state of the device and laternatives for action</li>

<li><strong>Good Conseptual Model</strong>: consistency/coherenc in presentations of operations, results, system image</li>

<li><strong>Mapping</strong>: actions ⬄ results, controls ⬄ effects, system state ⬄ what&#8217;s visible</li>
</ul>

<h3 id='design_questions'>Design Questions</h3>

<p><img alt='Ask Design Questions using the Seven Stages' src='/images/2012-10-17-chapter-2/seven-stages-questions.png' /></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chapter 1: The Psychopathology of Everyday Things]]></title>
    <link href="http://yangsu.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/chapter-1-the-psychopathology-of-everyday-things/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T17:52:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yangsu.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/chapter-1-the-psychopathology-of-everyday-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The human mind is exquisitely tailored to make sense of the world. Give it the slightest clue and off it goes, providing explanation, rationalization, and understanding.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id='introduction'>Introduction</h2>

<p>This chapter of <a href='http://www.amazon.com/Design-Everyday-Things-Donald-Norman/dp/0465067107' title='The Design of Everyday Things'>The Design of Everyday Things</a> introduces and formalizes basic concepts and principles of design from observations of everyday objects. Why some objects, as simple as doors, please their users while others frustrate them.</p>
<!-- more -->
<h2 id='definitions'>Definitions</h2>

<ul>
<li>
<p><strong id='visibility'>Visibility</strong>: correct parts must be visible, they must convey the correct messages; indicates the mapping between <em>intended actions</em> and <em>actual operations</em></p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong id='affordance'>Affordance</strong>: the perceived and actual properties of the thing, primarily the fundamental properties that determine how it can be used. <em>Affords</em> = <em>&#8220;is for&#8221;</em></p>

<p><em>Examples</em>:</p>

<p><img alt='horizontal bar  pushing (www.vanseodesign.com/web-design/minimize-errors-part-i)' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/door-push-bar.jpeg' /></p>

<p><img alt='vertical bar  pulling (www.flickr.com/photos/redsquirrel/4870919966/sizes/m/in/photostream)' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/door-pull-handle.jpeg' /></p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong id='system-image'>System Image</strong>: the visible part of a device or system</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong id='mental-model'>Mental Models</strong>: the models people have for themselves, others, the environment, and things with which they interact. Formed through experience, training, instructions, or by interpreting perceived actions and the <a href='#system-image'>System Image</a></p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong>Mapping</strong> : the relationship between two things <em>Example</em>: controls ⇒ their resulting movements and the effects in the physical world</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong id='natural-mapping'>Natural Mapping</strong>: <a href='#mapping'>mapping</a> that takes advantage of physical/spatial analogies and cultural standards <em>Examples</em>:</p>

<p><img alt='Rising Level ⇒ More' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/rising-level.png' /> <img alt='Diminishing Level ⇒ Less' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/diminishing-level.png' /></p>

<p>- <strong>Additive Dimensions</strong>: add more to show incremental increases <em>Examples</em>: amount, loudness, weight, length, brightness, etc.</p>

<p>- <strong>Substitutive Dimensions</strong>: substitute one value for another to make a change <em>Examples</em>: pitch, taste, color, location</p>
</li>

<li>
<p><strong>Feedback</strong>: sending back information to users about what actions have been performed <em>Example</em>: <img alt='Phones provide lots of feedback' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/phone.png' /> - Tactile feedback of buttons - Tones mapped for each button - Clicks, tones, to inform state and progress of a call or operation - <em>Sidetones</em>, the voice signal feedback into the ear to help regulate loudness</p>
</li>
</ul>

<h2 id='principles-of-design'>Principles of Design</h2>

<ol>
<li>
<p>Provide a good conceptual model - The proper <a href='#system-image'>System Image</a> and immediate <a href='#feedback'>feedback</a> for each operation can help users form a clear, concise, and correct <a href='#mental-model'>mental model</a></p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Make Things Visible</p>

<ul>
<li>Use good <a href='#natural-mapping'>natural mappings</a> and proper <a href='#visibility'>visibility</a> to help the user understand of possible operations, their effects, and the system state</li>

<li>The number of controls should be ≧ the number of functions a device performs, so each can be specifically mapped to a particular function</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>

<h2 id='designers-responsibility'>Designer&#8217;s Responsibility</h2>

<p>The Designer must balance the conflicting needs of others that help realize a product design:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Manufacturer</em>: the product can be produced economically and efficiently</li>

<li><em>Store</em>: the product should be attractive to customers</li>

<li><em>Purchaser</em>: the price, appearance, prestige value of a product at the Store</li>

<li><em>User</em>: the functionality and usability of a product at home</li>

<li><em>Repairer</em>: the product&#8217;s maintainability; how easy it is to take apart, diagnose, and service</li>
</ul>

<h2 id='development-of-a-technology'>Development of a Technology</h2>

<p><img alt='Development of a Technology' src='/images/2012-10-14-chapter-1/development-of-a-technology.png' /></p>

<h2 id='the-paradox-of-technology'>The Paradox of Technology</h2>

<p>The same technology that simplifies life by providing more functions in each device also complicates life by making the device harder to learn and use</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Design of Everyday Things]]></title>
    <link href="http://yangsu.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/the-design-of-everyday-things/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T11:27:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yangsu.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/the-design-of-everyday-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Everyday tasks are not difficult because of their inherent complexity - they are difficult only because they require learning arbitrary relationships and mappings, and because they sometimes require precision in their execution.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class='alignright' style='margin-left: 20px; margin-top: 8px;'><img alt='Teapot For Masochists' src='/images/teapot-for-masochists.jpeg' style='max-height: 360px;' /></p>

<p>Design is something that I&#8217;ve always wanted to learn, but never received a formal introduction to. It&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve always emulated but always fail to create. With Design and UX of products becoming increasingly important as a differentiator for startups and a means to establish a memorable brand image or memory of a product, it&#8217;s become even more imperative for me to learn Design.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the Computer Science department does not offer any courses in Human-Computer Interaction. Through a series of considerations, weighing the benefit of completing my graduation requirements this semester and having the option of graduating early, versus not having to suffer through yet another class that fails to interest me and using my extra class slot for something of my own choosing. I decided to go with the latter, due to many factors I will not get into here. Regardless, I definitely think I&#8217;ve made the right choice.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>Per one of my friend&#8217;s suggestion, I decided to pursue an Independent Research Study in Human-Computer Interaction with a focus on Interface Design and Data Visualization under Professor Duvall.</p>

<p>To build the foundations in Design, Professor Duvall suggested that I read three books, <a href='http://www.amazon.com/Design-Everyday-Things-Donald-Norman/dp/0465067107/'>The Design of Everyday Things</a>, <a href='http://www.amazon.com/Universal-Principles-Design-Revised-Updated/dp/1592535879/'>Universal Principles of Design</a>, and <a href='http://www.amazon.com/Interaction-Design-Beyond-Human-Computer/dp/0470018666/'>Interaction Design</a>, as an introduction to the vocabulary and language of Design. <a href='http://www.amazon.com/Design-Everyday-Things-Donald-Norman/dp/0465067107/'>The Design of Everyday Things</a>, the seminal work in Design by cognitive scientist and usability engineer Donald Norman from the 1980s, is a particularly enjoyable read. It formalizes design principles from careful observations of mundane everyday objects. Below are the 7 main principles discussed in the book to transform a difficult task into a simple one.</p>

<h4 id='1_use_both_knowledge_in_the_world_and_knowledge_in_the_head'>1. Use Both Knowledge in the World and Knowledge in the Head</h4>

<p>For first time or infrequent users, knowledge required for a task should be available either <strong>explicitly in the world</strong> or <strong>derived from constraints in the environment</strong>. There should be a natural, easily interpreted relationship between the knowledge and the information it&#8217;s intended to convey.</p>

<p>For frequent users, Design should not impede action and allow users to be more efficient at a particular task, especially for people who have internalized the knowledge. It should be easy to go back and forth between using knowledge in the world and knowledge in the head and the two should coexist without interference.</p>

<h4 id='2_simplify_the_structure_of_tasks'>2. Simplify the Structure of Tasks</h4>

<p>Eliminate or restructure complexities, minimizing the planning and problem solving a task requires. Pay attention to the psychology of a user and the limits on memory and attention.</p>

<ul>
<li>Use reminders by providing knowledge in the world and reduce the mental load of the trivial parts of a task * Keep the tasks much the same, but provide mental aids Use mental aids for facts essential to everyday functioning, but cannot trust memory structures to provide * Use tech to make the invisible visible, improving feedback and ability to keep control Use graphical displays to inform the user of the system state and make important information visible and accessible and the irrelevant info hidden</li>

<li>Automate, but keep tasks much the same * Parts of an automated task will disappear, there&#8217;s always a trade off. * Ideally, a user should be able to choose automation or full control * Don&#8217;t take away control * over automation can eliminate a person&#8217;s ability to function without it, and a major problem if the automation fails * Can be inflexible as the system may not do exactly what&#8217;s required because altering the automation is too difficult * Maintain layers of control and produce automation at each layer so we can switch and be flexible</li>

<li>Change the nature of the task Technology can help transform deep and wide structures into shallow, narrow ones<br />Shoelances vs Vecro</li>
</ul>

<h4 id='3_make_things_visible_bridge_the_gulfs_of_execution_and_evaluations'>3. Make Things Visible: Bridge the Gulfs of Execution and Evaluations</h4>

<p>Easy to see what&#8217;s visible: what can be done and what their effects are.<br />Actions should match intentions<br />It&#8217;s important to make the correct things visible so the users for the correct interpretations and mental models through the system image</p>

<h4 id='4_get_the_mappings_right'>4. Get the Mappings Right</h4>

<p>Natural Mappings (&#8220;response compatibility&#8221;): the the spatial relationships between the controls and the system components or objects they control should be as <strong>direct</strong> as possible, with the controls and the objects themselves or have an analogical relationship<br />The movements of the control should be similar or analogous to the expected operation of the system.<br />feedback must be timely and easy to understand</p>

<h4 id='5_explore_the_power_of_constraints_both_natural_and_artificial'>5. Explore the Power of Constraints, Both Natural and Artificial</h4>

<p>Reduce the number of possible alternative actions at each step to a few or ideally just one</p>

<h4 id='6_design_for_error'>6. Design for Error</h4>

<p>Assume errors will be made. Allow for recovery. Use forcing functions<br />Each user action is an attempt to a step in the right direction<br />An error is incompletely or improperly specified actions</p>

<h4 id='7_when_all_fails_standardize'>7. When All Fails, Standardize</h4>

<p>Standardize the problem and processes, so arbitrary mappings only have to be learned once<br />It maybe difficult to obtain an agreement, early enough to save trouble later on, and late enough to take into account of the existing technologies and procedures<br />Standardization is only essential when all necessary information cannot be placed in the world or when normal mapping cannot be exploited<br />Users must be trained for this</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
